Ayesha Hamad . Jarvis Consulting

I have done BS in Computer Science and have 3 years of programming experience application development. I have also done short courses, Full Stack Java Development and Software Quality Assurance - Manual and Automation Testing. To pursue my career further in Software Development and Quality Assurance, I also took some certifications, I am Certified Automation Tester, SCRUM Tester, and Manual Tester. What really excites me is that the Software industry is ruling the world and I always wanted to be a part of it. I like to code and develop apps and programs and doing what you like most increases your creativity and productivity as well. I have excellent communication and interpersonal skills and am always willing to learn new technologies and adapting new environment.

Skills

Proficient: Java, C++, OOP, Data Structures, Linux/Bash, RDBMS/SQL, JDBC, Maven, Docker/Docker Hub, SDLC, Agile/Scrum, Git/GitHub, IntelliJ, Dbeaver

Competent: Test scripting using UFT (QTP), Selenium WebDriver (JAVA) implementing Page Object Model and TestNG, ALM Octane (QC), Jira, Manual Testing/Test cases

Familiar: Obj-C, C# .Net, Rest API, SOAP UI - Testing Web Services, Web designing

Jarvis Projects

Project source code: https://github.com/jarviscanada/jarvis data eng AyeshaHamad

Cluster Monitor [GitHub]: Implemented a Monitoring Agent for the Linux admin team with Bash Scripts, PostgreSQL, PSQL Client Tool, Crontab, SQL queries, Docker, etc. The LCA team can get hardware specifications and software utilization like memory/CPU management, and generate reports with the help of the data saved in the database and executing SQL queries. These reports will further help the LCA team to make decisions either they want to increase hardware/software specifications or not if the system is fully or underutilized.

Core Java Apps [GitHub]:

- JDBC App: Designed a 'Customer Order Processing System' using JDBC, Data Access Object (DAO), and Data Transfer Object (DTO) Design Pattern, Postgres SQL, PSQL Client Tool, Maven, Docker to create Psql container, IntelliJ, and DBeaver. I have used JDBC to access data from RDBMS. The advantage of JDBC is that an application created using JDBC can access a variety of relational databases and run on any platform with a Java Virtual Machine. In this application, you can read, write, update, and delete (CURD) data against an RDBMS database.
- Grep App: Created a program to search a string from text files using ArrayList, FileReader/FileWriter, BufferedReader/BufferedWriter, Regex Pattern, Maven, and Docker to dockerize the app. This program works in a way that it traverses the 'root directory' that you enter and looks for files and sub-directories further in it. Searches the entered string in all those files and saves all matching lines to a text file.

Highlighted Projects

Photo Editor - Filters and Effect: Created Photo Editor app using C++ and OpenCV library. Added number of filters manipulating RBG pixels of the image with the help of OpenCV.

Professional Experiences

Software Developer, Jarvis (2021-present): Working as a Software Developer, creating Java Applications using Core Java concepts, OOP, Data Structures, RDBMS/SQL, JDBC, Maven etc. Implementing SCRUM and AGILE methodologies and appropriate SDLC, analyzing Business Requirements and Functional Specifications, identifying Test Scenarios and deploying the app.

Software Engineer, FiveRivers Technologies, Lahore, Pakistan (2011-2014): Worked on Marmalade - a cross platform for mobile application development using C++ and developed android and IOS applications. My basic dedication was creating the Photo Editor app in pepper.pk integrating openCV and photo shop algorithms to create filters. Key Responsibilities: Created Photo Editor App using Marmalade, for android and IOS. Created android and IOS extensions to add monetization s and other SDKs to marmalade platform like Revmob, StartApp, Leadbolt, Google Ad mediation, Flurry, Crittercism using JNI, Java, Obj-C and marmalade EDK (extension development kit). Maintained existing programs by modifying as required and making the code reusable. Wrote, modified, integrated, and tested software code.

Wrote test cases for each module to ensure a bug free and robust code. Gathered and Understood user requirements to develop logical specifications.

Education

Punjab University, Lahore, Pakistan (2007-2011), Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, College of Information and Technology

Com IT, Winnipeg, Canada (June 2018-Sep 2018), Full Stack Java Development, IT

Justwin IT Solutions, Brampton, Canada (Jan 2021-Apr 2021), Quality Assurance: Manual and Automation Testing, IT

Miscellaneous

- Endorsed Automation Tester Certification
- Endorsed Manual Tester Certification
- Endorsed Scrum Tester Certification